# Shubham Shilvane

### Front-End Developer

Passionate Frontend Developer with overall 4 years of IT industry experience. Hands on experience with the concepts and implementations of HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap3&4, Javascript, AJAX, ES6, Flex and Angular, Angular material. Eagerly expanding skills into Backend, dedicated to ongoing learning and staying abreast of industry trends for proactive Developers.

✓ shubhamshilvane1296@gmail.com

+919637014535

Hyderabad, India vercel.com/shubhams-projects-bede0601

in linkedin.com/in/shubhamshilvane https://github.com/Shubham-96k

### PORTFOLIO:

Shubham - A Web Developer (shubham96k-portfolio-site.vercel.app)

# WORK EXPERIENCE :

# Frontend Angular Developer

OSSS Consulting services Pvt Ltd. 05/2022 - Present

Nizamabad, India

#### Key roles and responsibilities:

- Led the front-end development for an E-commerce domain, ensuring a seamless and user-friendly experience. The major services include sales of electrical accessories like transformers, solar panels, motors and batteries.
- Created different modules, components using Angular Material, pipes and directives in Angular as per business requirements.
- Implemented responsive web design techniques to ensure that the e-commerce website functions well across various devices and screen sizes, providing a consistent user experience on desktops, tablets, and smartphones.
- Implementation of different types of Quotation forms using reactive forms in Angular and TD form for Login and Signup Component.
- Optimized the frontend performance by applying best practices such as code splitting, lazy loading, and caching.
- Monitor and analyze website performance metrics (e.g., page load time, time to interact) to identify and address performance bottlenecks Overcame data integration challenges in the user module implementing a custom API, ensuring accurate and up-to-date information to users.

# Frontend Developer (XPORIENCE)

OSSS Consulting services Pvt Ltd.

05/2021 - 05/2022

Nizamabad, India

#### Key roles and responsibilities:

- Converted PSD into responsive HTML using Bootstrap 3.
- Created interactions using JavaScript/jQuery.
- Used ¡Query Plugins.
- Fixing issues raised by team.
- Responsive website for browser & environmental compatibility on every devices.

# <u>Application Support Engineer</u>

OSSS Consulting services Pvt Ltd. 05/2020-05/2021

Nizamabad, India

#### Key roles and responsibilities:

- Coordinated with Level 1 technical support specialists to take over calls outside their level of support.
- Assisted customers with more difficult technical issues requiring a greater level of personalized care and in greater length.
- diagnose and troubleshoot software and hardware problems and help our clients install applications and programs.
- Escalated support desk tickets to Level 3 in the most crucial circumstances.
- On boarded and trained all incoming junior tech support specialists.

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Contributed Ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements in the angular project received positive feedback from users, leading to 15% increase in user engagement.
- Received a lot of appreciation from the team for quick learning and implementation.
- Received a lot of appreciation from the client for smooth delivery of the project.

SKILLS:	Angular 10		Angular Material		TypeScript		JavaScript, ES6		S3
	SASS	HTML5	Bootstra	ap(3&4)	AJAX	NGB	ootstrap	FLEX	}
	RXJS	jQuery	NPM	GIT/GITH	IUB RW	/D	Media Queri	ies	
TOOLS:	Visual studio Code Vercel Postman Firebase Jira jQuery-Plugins								
	Augury Chrome Developer Tool ANGULAR-CLI					FontAwe	esome		

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelor's Degree**

SRTMU Nanded

06/2017 - 11/2020

# Intermediate (11th & 12th)

Swami Vivekanand College

06/2015 - 06/2017

Courses:

MPC (Mathematics & Statistics, Physics & Chemistry)

#### LANGUAGES

Marathi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Hindi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

**English** 

Full Professional Proficiency